

CONTACT

- 0728726668
- youngbk0308@gmail.com
- 63 Olive Road, EASTRIDGE, Mitchell's Plain, 7785
- https://bit.ly/3SXCMej



https://byron-young-portfoliov2.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

Jan 2021 - Dec 2023

Cape Peninsula University of **Technology**

DPICTADIP: ICT in Applications Development

Jan 2008 - Dec 2012

Princeton High School

National Senior Certificate

TECH STACKS



English (Fluent)

BYRON YOUNG

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Junior software developer with two years' experience in a software development environment. I have completed my diploma in Information & Communication Technology at Cape Peninsula University of Technology. I am an excellent communicator, problem solver, and team player. My career objective is to become a Full Stack Developer, as I am constantly seeking opportunities to learn new technologies to improve my skills. I am excited to bring my skills and passion to a new role in the field of software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Cape Peninsula University of Technology JULY 2023 - DEC 2023 Intern Developer
 - Assisted in editing and maintaining project documentation.
 - Developed a Virtual Machine request application.
 - · Worked with team members using GitHub for version control and collaboration.

University of Western Cape

MAY 2018 - MAY 2019

Intern Developer

- · Worked closely with a senior developer to design and implement an application utilizing SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS).
- Assisted in documentation and quality assurance processes.
- Collaborating with team members on GitHub.

Web 2 Web

MAY 2017 - NOV 2017

Intern Web Developer

- · Designed and developed webpages for clients, ensuring responsiveness and
- Managed and updated website content to align with client requirements.
- Implemented SEO best practices to enhance client online visibility.

PROJECTS

Good Eats Restaurant ASP.NET MVC Web Application

I developed a restaurant order web application using ASP.NET MVC and Razor Pages, utilizing Microsoft SQL Server for database management. ASP.NET Identity was implemented for secure authentication and role-based authorization. Sessions have been integrated into user-specific cart tracking, enabling easy ordering. I designed a user-friendly interface to allow customers to browse menus and place orders, along with a dashboard for administrators to manage their menus and orders. Deployed the application on Microsoft Azure using Azure App Services and Azure SQL Database, ensuring high availability, scalability, and security.

REFERENCE

Ageel Bucks

University of Western Cape

Position: Senior Developer

Phone: 0613548781

Malibongwe Dywibiba

Cape Peninsula University of Technology

Position: ICT Department Supervisor

Phone: 083 494 2638